<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathematical Michael on Mathematical Michael</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mathematical Michael on Mathematical Michael</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Michael Pilosov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Math || Art</title>
      <link>/post/mathart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mathart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&#34;refresh&#34; content=&#34;0; url=https://michaelpilosov.com/project/mathart/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&#34;refresh&#34; content=&#34;0; url=../post&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&#34;refresh&#34; content=&#34;0; url=../project&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientist Spotlight Series: Mika McKinnon</title>
      <link>/post/mika/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Pi Day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In celebration of this wonderful number, today I thought I&amp;rsquo;d highlight a scientist who is out there in the wild doing math and weaving it into the content we consume. Meet Mika McKinnon:
&lt;center&gt; &lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Hi! I&amp;#39;m a disaster researcher (landslides in space with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ESPRESSO_SSERVI?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@ESPRESSO_SSERVI&lt;/a&gt;!), TV &amp;amp; movie science consultant, field geophysicist, &amp;amp; freelance science communicator. I&amp;#39;m usually somewhere along the West Coast of North America.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Easiest way to contact me is &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/7YGZMmSGrN&#34;&gt;https://t.co/7YGZMmSGrN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/UyWIwa0P2G&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/UyWIwa0P2G&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Mika McKinnon (@mikamckinnon) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mikamckinnon/status/972581146373406720?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
 &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across her Twitter yesterday while I was sheltering-in-place during the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.denverpost.com/2019/03/13/colorado-weather-bomb-cyclone-blizzard/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;bomb cyclone&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; hitting Denver, and this tweet jumped out at me immediately (I ❤️2️⃣👀 &lt;em&gt;math&lt;/em&gt; on social media):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt; &lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Stargate, some Star Trek: Discovery, a bit of Madam Secretary, a whole lot of No Tomorrow, some kids shows... My math is all over your tv shows ;)&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Mika McKinnon (@mikamckinnon) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mikamckinnon/status/1105672294058414081?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 13, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
 &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I jumped into the conversation (thanks, Twitter!) and let my curiosity get the best of me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt; &lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Sure; ping via &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/tExPpQugTr&#34;&gt;https://t.co/tExPpQugTr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Top tip: Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SciEntExchange?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@SciEntExchange&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For me? Right place, right time for the start; maintaining my network everything afterwards&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Mika McKinnon (@mikamckinnon) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mikamckinnon/status/1105702603453796353?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 13, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
 &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arranged a time to speak this morning and I was delighted to hear about her journey through &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.library.ubc.ca/cIRcle/collections/ubctheses/24/items/1.0052933&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;geophysics&lt;/a&gt; to consulting on the scientific integrity in modern storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; I have selected some highlights from the interview to address how she got involved with this facet of science communication, but I am saving some of her stories for future blog posts (complete with pictures and sources to more scientific information!). &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve got an impressive history on some big shows. How did you get involved in the film and television industry?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in grad school doing disaster work. I actually started with volcanos on Mars and then ended up doing landslides on Earth! I was in Vancouver, which is nicknamed Hollywood North because we have so much SciFi filmed there &amp;hellip; all these alien planets look like the Pacific Northwest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day we got a call for the physics department saying &amp;ldquo;we need a string theorist!&amp;rdquo; I wasn&amp;rsquo;t a string theorist but my buddy Steve was&amp;hellip; he literally put his research notes up on the sets of Stargate; he published string theory in Stargate three years before his dissertation.
It was really fun, and I quickly realized that they didn&amp;rsquo;t actually need a &amp;ldquo;string theorist;&amp;rdquo; that was just the fanciest scientist they could think of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Steve left &amp;hellip; and they came back looking for him, I went &amp;ldquo;you don&amp;rsquo;t need a string theorist! You need me.&amp;rdquo;
So I showed up on set, &amp;hellip; I have no idea what my original instructions were, but apparently I did well enough that I then got invited to come back the next day, and the next day, and the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vancouver is not just a city where a lot of SciFi films are made, it&amp;rsquo;s a city where a lot of &lt;em&gt;unionized&lt;/em&gt; SciFi films are made. People leave &amp;hellip; and they remember who they worked with &amp;hellip; then work on other amazing shows. I end up working on all these other shows because someone has my cell phone number from ten years ago and I&amp;rsquo;ll get a call saying &amp;ldquo;Hey, can you show up on set, like, tomorrow?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wow, you nailed the summary in the tweet. Right place and time plus maintaining a network! What was it like on set once you got there?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the more unusual parts about this was because they want real math and they want real science, and there&amp;rsquo;s a script that gives you an idea of what the subject matter is. Mostly they&amp;rsquo;d give me instructions like &amp;ldquo;we need six feet of equations,&amp;rdquo; and I&amp;rsquo;d respond with &amp;ldquo;six feet of equations on what?&amp;rdquo; And they go &amp;ldquo;just six feet!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up doing a lot of things like, say, &lt;strong&gt;feed the energy of a solar flare into a black hole,&lt;/strong&gt; which although mathematically valid, is just not something you&amp;rsquo;d ever do in real life. I got the opportunity to do generally novel mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of movies and TV shows will hire a specialist to do science at them and leave, but on Stargate I built up a relationship, one of trust. At the beginning, I was working for the property department (things actors would interact with), and I&amp;rsquo;d get lent out to the &amp;ldquo;set dec&amp;rdquo; (set decoration department), and maybe VFX (&amp;ldquo;video effects&amp;rdquo;) would need me for something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, as I would reliably worked for them and was friendly, always answering questions between takes &amp;hellip; I came to understand that this is not a science lesson, it is &lt;em&gt;a story with science in it, so story always comes first&lt;/em&gt;. We eventually came to the point where the writing department would come to me with something like &amp;ldquo;our starship is running out of oxygen, we need to go to an alien planet. How do they find the rocks they need to fix this?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What was your favorite prompt?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The writers came to me with], &amp;ldquo;we need an astrophysical big baddie that kills every body every twenty-two minutes,&amp;rdquo; which was by far my favorite thing I ever got to do at Stargate. Their original idea was a really &lt;strong&gt;slowly rotating pulsar.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, a pulsar rotates on the order of milliseconds. A slow pulsar &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; rotates in milliseconds, so if you had one that rotated so its beam would cross every twenty-two &lt;em&gt;minutes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;the electromagnetic field would be about as deadly as holding refrigerator magnets and do cartwheels.&lt;/strong&gt; Sure, it would generate an electromagnetic field, but it&amp;rsquo;s not one anyone would even notice, much less kill somebody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my idea was to have a &amp;ldquo;starving pulsar,&amp;rdquo; one right on the brink of being able to pulse and not pulse, and put it in a binary star system, where one feeder star would zip by really close to a bigger star, and sap off some of that plasma and dust&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the time we did this episode, we never saw a system like this in real life&lt;/strong&gt;, but we did see that pulsars &lt;em&gt;could be in binary system&lt;/em&gt;, and we knew there were such thing as an inactive pulsar, so we went &amp;ldquo;eh, this is plausible. why not?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three years later, scientists found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K971tt40iJw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;such a system&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:These-rotated-at&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:These-rotated-at&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in real life! So I was super proud that &lt;strong&gt;we hypothesized this in Stargate as a major plot point three years before it was discovered.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I love the way you&amp;rsquo;re just like&amp;hellip; sneaking things into pop-culture this way. It&amp;rsquo;s so wonderfully subversive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah, I have so many references to my friends&amp;rsquo; thesis work in various episodes of Stargate&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much that all my physics classmates have some sort of reference to their work somewhere on the blackboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That is incredible! How many people are there in similar roles?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very very few, as far as I know. There have been Science Consultants for a long time, going back to Star Trek, before I was even born.
But most people who do science consulting either do one show or movie and then never again, or they do a little bit of it and then transition into script writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, I am the longest running one &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s been over a decade at this point &amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;m still doing science consulting as opposed to script writing. There are a handful of other people working on high-profile shows, but there are very few women, and they usually just do one-off engagements. It&amp;rsquo;s not for a lack of want, it just seems that they haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people in science are deep fans of sci-fi, and it&amp;rsquo;s such a common idea that &amp;ldquo;if only they talked to me first, they could have fixed this idea.&amp;rdquo; But it turns out it is much easier to destroy than create&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a game of &amp;ldquo;yes-and&amp;rdquo; improvisation&amp;hellip; &lt;strong&gt;they&amp;rsquo;re going to do the story they&amp;rsquo;re going to do, and your job is to make it &lt;em&gt;plausible&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; You will run into situations that may make you cringe a bit&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s okay to sacrifice some scientific integrity for the sake of story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, and that&amp;rsquo;s exactly where you have to be. You have to understand that story comes first. It&amp;rsquo;s all about the story and that we have some scientific plausibility there is great, but it is not the primary function of the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And what would you suggest to those interested in Science Communication as far as conferences, organizations, etc?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those looking to get involved, the National Academies of Sciences &amp;ldquo;Entertainment Exchange&amp;rdquo; is a great place to start. It&amp;rsquo;s primarily one-off conversations, but it can lead to paid work. I consider it a great way to &lt;em&gt;learn the process&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure out how to teach &lt;em&gt;quickly&lt;/em&gt;, get to the high-end stuff first so [the writers] can pick between options, and then start running down what the various consequences would be, what could be incorporated as story-telling elements. How does it also play out in the details and how are they part of the world-building?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the sorts of mindsets to put yourself in. As far as getting into the industry, look out for media fellowships and internships from organizations like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.agu.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AGU&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aaas.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AAAS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nationalacademies.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The National Academies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aip.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AIP&lt;/a&gt;, and various other subject-specific groups. Many even offer discounted legal services for members that freelance science communicators should definitely try to take advantage of!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scicommcamp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SciComm Camp&lt;/a&gt; is an excellent event, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nasw.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;National Association of Science Writers&lt;/a&gt; does a lot in this space. You can also look for local groups, and even volunteer to work with Creative Writing workshops to hone these kinds of skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there it is, put yourself in situations that facilitate networking, and maintain relationships you form in the industry. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave you with one of my favorite quotes from our conversation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My job is to be curious and excited in public, and it&amp;rsquo;s all just different facets of that job.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:These-rotated-at&#34;&gt;These rotated at 38 minute intervals! Which would have been perfect had the episodes been twice as long. &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:These-rotated-at&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matplotlib Scatter Plots</title>
      <link>/post/matplotlib/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 07:41:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/matplotlib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I ran into a problem while upgrading code from Python 2 to Python 3 that required me to downgrade &lt;code&gt;matplotlib&lt;/code&gt; to version &lt;code&gt;2.2.3&lt;/code&gt; in order to get the functionality in place (all tests were passing except for plotting).
Once that dust settled, I attempted to individually upgrade to &lt;code&gt;matplotlib==3.0.2&lt;/code&gt; and ran into trouble with how &lt;code&gt;scatter&lt;/code&gt; parses color sequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a lot of trouble finding a good solution online, but after sifting through a lot of forums and GitHub issues&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:github&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:github&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and trying many permutations of different syntaxes, I finally came around to a &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; solution that passed the tests as they were written.
The issue was that the &lt;code&gt;color&lt;/code&gt; argument must match the type of the &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; inputs into &lt;code&gt;scatter&lt;/code&gt;, which was not the case before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code I was working with formed &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; by indexing a 2-d &lt;code&gt;np.array&lt;/code&gt; (call it &lt;code&gt;data&lt;/code&gt;), and I found that using &lt;code&gt;np.reshape&lt;/code&gt; as follows led to the easiest backwards-compatible solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;# inds represents indices
x = data[inds, 0]
y = data[inds, 1]
c = colors[inds] # colors is passed to be height of some function that takes x and y as inputs.
plt.scatter(np.reshape(x,-1), 
            np.reshape(y,-1), 
            c=np.reshape(c,-1),
            cmap=color_map) # color_map defined elsewhere
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If &lt;code&gt;inds&lt;/code&gt; is length-1 or length-N, this syntax still works and respects the new requirements for coloring scatterplots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:github&#34;&gt;Places where the issue is mentioned or discussed: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/matplotlib/matplotlib/issues/12429&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;#12429&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/matplotlib/matplotlib/issues/10365&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;#10365&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:github&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Subspaces</title>
      <link>/post/activesubspaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/activesubspaces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I ran a series of tests and google searches to convert a repository to Python 3 from Python 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;2to3&lt;/code&gt; was a good starting point but the &lt;code&gt;imports&lt;/code&gt; needed a lot of restructuring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the other problems were all related to division operations. The default type is now Float, so &lt;code&gt;1/2&lt;/code&gt; returns &lt;code&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt;, whereas in Python 2 it returns &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; since the numerator is interpreted as an integer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Drank coffee WAY too late in the evening and converted &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DrPaulynomial?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@DrPaulynomial&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ActiveSubspaces?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#ActiveSubspaces&lt;/a&gt; repo to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Python3?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#Python3&lt;/a&gt;. Got to use my hub at &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/cYaLs3Qabi&#34;&gt;https://t.co/cYaLs3Qabi&lt;/a&gt; for development in a fresh environment, too! &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/mathematics?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#mathematics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/appliedmathematics?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#appliedmathematics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/computationalmathematics?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#computationalmathematics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/python2to3?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#python2to3&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/dev?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#dev&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/30bprcephv&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/30bprcephv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Mathematical Michael (@mindthemaths) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mindthemaths/status/1085431034261336065?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 16, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/paulcon/active_subspaces/pull/52&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; in that image now needs to be merged, and likely amended with some Travis CI instructions to test for Python 3.6. At the very least, my passing status reflects backwards compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;script
  src=&#34;https://cdn.rawgit.com/IonicaBizau/github-calendar/gh-pages/dist/github-calendar.min.js&#34;
&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;





&lt;div class=&#34;calendar&#34;&gt;
    
    Loading the data just for you.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
    new GitHubCalendar(&#34;.calendar&#34;, &#34;mathematicalmichael&#34;);
&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These set of commits mark my 20th contribution.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/activity&#34;&gt;Full Activity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Activity</title>
      <link>/activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/activity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a summary of my activity on Github from my new username.
The primary repository is my thesis. I will gradually add public-facing projects here as well.

&lt;script
  src=&#34;https://cdn.rawgit.com/IonicaBizau/github-calendar/gh-pages/dist/github-calendar.min.js&#34;
&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;





&lt;div class=&#34;calendar&#34;&gt;
    
    Loading the data just for you.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
    new GitHubCalendar(&#34;.calendar&#34;, &#34;mathematicalmichael&#34;);
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For activity on my other profile, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.michaelpilosov.com/activity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my other website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probably Art # 365: Walk</title>
      <link>/artwork/rnr_walks_0001422527/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 04:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/artwork/rnr_walks_0001422527/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../artwork/images/walk_[000_006_1422527]_r[Betax058_001_[1000_1000]_t[Beta360_006_[1000_1000]].png&#34; alt=&#34;artwork-here&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;250 steps in 6 direction(s) chosen from 1 possible step size(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$ s = .01422527, \; $$
$$ | \lbrace \theta \rbrace | = 6, $$
$$  | \lbrace r \rbrace | = 1,$$
$$ r_0 = 0.0000,$$
$$ R = 0.58, $$
$$r \sim \beta(1.000, 1.000), $$
$$\theta \sim \beta(1.000, 1.000). $$&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probably Art # 364: Polygon</title>
      <link>/artwork/rnr_polygons_0000292954/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 01:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/artwork/rnr_polygons_0000292954/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../artwork/images/blob_[1834_009_2500]_r[Betax100_90000_[25000_44000]_t[Beta360_1835_[1000_1000]].png&#34; alt=&#34;artwork-here&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1834-sided polygon with vertices chosen from 9 distance(s) from the origin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$ s = .00292954, \; $$
$$ | \lbrace \theta \rbrace | = 1834, $$
$$  | \lbrace r \rbrace | = 9,$$
$$ r_0 = 0.2500,$$
$$ R = 1.00, $$
$$r \sim \beta(25.000, 44.000), $$
$$\theta \sim \beta(1.000, 1.000). $$&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probably Art # 363: Line</title>
      <link>/artwork/rnr_lines_0000035708/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 23:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/artwork/rnr_lines_0000035708/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../artwork/images/line_[054_038]_r[Betax300_90000_[857_597]_t[Beta180_20000_[1442_790]]_S35708L1V1C0s0r0.png&#34; alt=&#34;artwork-here&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2052 lines drawn through each origin in one of 2 direction(s) with lengths chosen from 8 size(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$ s = .00035708, \; $$
$$ | \lbrace \theta \rbrace | = 2, $$
$$  | \lbrace r \rbrace | = 8,$$
$$ r_0 = 0.0000,$$
$$ R = 3.00, $$
$$r \sim \beta(0.857, 0.597), $$
$$\theta \sim \beta(1.442, 0.790). $$&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probably Art # 362: Walk</title>
      <link>/artwork/rnr_walks_0001240218/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 13:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/artwork/rnr_walks_0001240218/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../artwork/images/walk_[000_012_1240218]_r[Betax019_001_[1000_1000]_t[Beta360_012_[1000_1000]].png&#34; alt=&#34;artwork-here&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;250 steps in 12 direction(s) chosen from 1 possible step size(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$ s = .01240218, \; $$
$$ | \lbrace \theta \rbrace | = 12, $$
$$  | \lbrace r \rbrace | = 1,$$
$$ r_0 = 0.0000,$$
$$ R = 0.20, $$
$$r \sim \beta(1.000, 1.000), $$
$$\theta \sim \beta(1.000, 1.000). $$&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probably Art # 361: Walk</title>
      <link>/artwork/rnr_walks_0000126595/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 23:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/artwork/rnr_walks_0000126595/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../artwork/images/walk_[000_008_126595]_r[Betax033_001_[1000_1000]_t[Beta360_008_[1000_1000]].png&#34; alt=&#34;artwork-here&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;250 steps in 8 direction(s) chosen from 1 possible step size(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$ s = .00126595, \; $$
$$ | \lbrace \theta \rbrace | = 8, $$
$$  | \lbrace r \rbrace | = 1,$$
$$ r_0 = 0.0000,$$
$$ R = 0.34, $$
$$r \sim \beta(1.000, 1.000), $$
$$\theta \sim \beta(1.000, 1.000). $$&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probably Art # 360: Walk</title>
      <link>/artwork/rnr_walks_0004183970/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 16:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/artwork/rnr_walks_0004183970/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../artwork/images/walk_[000_010_4183970]_r[Betax008_008_[1000_1000]_t[Beta360_010_[1000_1000]].png&#34; alt=&#34;artwork-here&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;250 steps in 10 direction(s) chosen from 8 possible step size(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$ s = .04183970, \; $$
$$ | \lbrace \theta \rbrace | = 10, $$
$$  | \lbrace r \rbrace | = 8,$$
$$ r_0 = 0.0000,$$
$$ R = 0.09, $$
$$r \sim \beta(1.000, 1.000), $$
$$\theta \sim \beta(1.000, 1.000). $$&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probably Art # 359: Line</title>
      <link>/artwork/rnr_lines_0002575604/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 09:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/artwork/rnr_lines_0002575604/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../artwork/images/line_[009_023]_r[Betax400_90000_[37000_84000]_t[Beta180_80000_[3000_5000]]_S2575604L1V1C0s0r0.png&#34; alt=&#34;artwork-here&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;207 lines drawn through each origin in one of 8 direction(s) with lengths chosen from 8 size(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$ s = .02575604, \; $$
$$ | \lbrace \theta \rbrace | = 8, $$
$$  | \lbrace r \rbrace | = 8,$$
$$ r_0 = 0.0000,$$
$$ R = 4.00, $$
$$r \sim \beta(37.000, 84.000), $$
$$\theta \sim \beta(3.000, 5.000). $$&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probably Art # 358: Polygon</title>
      <link>/artwork/rnr_polygons_0003993850/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 16:08:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/artwork/rnr_polygons_0003993850/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../artwork/images/blob_[070_007_2500]_r[Betax100_70000_[32000_20000]_t[Beta360_071_[1000_1000]].png&#34; alt=&#34;artwork-here&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;70-sided polygon with vertices chosen from 7 distance(s) from the origin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$ s = .03993850, \; $$
$$ | \lbrace \theta \rbrace | = 70, $$
$$  | \lbrace r \rbrace | = 7,$$
$$ r_0 = 0.2500,$$
$$ R = 1.00, $$
$$r \sim \beta(32.000, 20.000), $$
$$\theta \sim \beta(1.000, 1.000). $$&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
